<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Schemavr1 on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/tags/schemavr1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Schemavr1 on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/tags/schemavr1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue with stimulus selection and some thoughts</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This entry contains thoughts and observations for the last couple of days because I was stuck with a problem and didn’t have a lot say. The problem was that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t controlled the number of times a location can serve as a foil when I had picked the set of object/locations pairs. This is indeed problematic because some locations were used four times. If you know which object was at a specific location, it isn’t really a foil anymore influencing subsequent trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing whether targets differ in rank from foils</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/testing-whether-targets-differ-in-rank-from-foils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/testing-whether-targets-differ-in-rank-from-foils/</guid>
      <description>Introduction On Friday I found a good combination of objects and locations (see here). Before I try this set in VR, it is important to make sure that the foils are not different from the targets in terms of the expectancy. To compare those, I calculate a repeated measure ANOVA and visualise it.
Used libraries and functions library(ggplot2) library(ez) library(tidyr) pValue &amp;lt;-function(x, sign = &#39;=&#39;){ if (inherits(x, &amp;quot;lm&amp;quot;)){ s &amp;lt;- summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulus selection for schemaVR1 (Attempt 1)</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/stimulus-selection-for-schemavr1-attempt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/stimulus-selection-for-schemavr1-attempt-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The aim is to select a certain number (20) of combinations of objects and locations that cover the whole range of expectancy values. The previous analysis of this data set can be found here. The code for the task can be found here.
Used libraries and functions library(ggplot2)  Loading the rating data I start with loading the raw data and creating a 20 x 20 x N matrix holding all 400 location ratings for all participants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>