<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ideas and plans on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/ideas-and-plans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ideas and plans on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ideas-and-plans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interim results and future plans</title>
      <link>/2018/04/interim-results-and-future-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/interim-results-and-future-plans/</guid>
      <description>I am currently caught up with collecting data for my first experiment, which I will henceforth call schemaVR1, working on my first year report and analysing the interim results. I have collected data from eight participant so far and already got number of significant results. This is quite impressive considering that I also have only twenty stimuli/trials. I will upload the pre-processing script alongside a script analysing the interim results in the next days in a separate GitHub repository, where I will provide more details, but a very robust, and already significant, finding is that the locations of unexpected objects are recalled more often than that of expected objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General update and plan for the future</title>
      <link>/2018/03/general-update-and-plan-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/general-update-and-plan-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Even though the last post is basically a month ago, I am still committed to this diary. Therefore I thought to provide an update. I spent the last month with finishing the experiment and preparing its pre-registration. In that progress, I have started working on the R script that analyses the data to include it in the pre-registration. I want to use mixed linear models to analyse the data so that I can model the performance on individual trials.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>