<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting</title>
      <link>/2018/12/lab-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/lab-meeting/</guid>
      <description>During our weekly lab meeting I got the following feedback pertaining to project 1 (schema-memory-VR; see here):
 I should drop mixed condition and only use unexpected or expected locations to reduce the number of conditions. Another idea was to present objects in a sequence in order to create a temporal episode. It could be interesting in this context to look at the fragmentation hypothesis (Horner &amp;amp; Burgess, 2013, 2014) and see how my VR approach can be use to examine predictions of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting and checking living/non-living words</title>
      <link>/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</guid>
      <description>Aim Here, I am selecting 200 words for a new project called noveltyVR, in which I am going to try to study the effect of novelty on something that was learned before. In this case, it will be a list of words that were incidentally encoded in a living/non-living judgement task. I will select 200 words from a published study, look up their properties in the MRC Psycholinguistic Database and create two lists that are used as old and new stimuli in a recognition task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing normative data set</title>
      <link>/2018/01/analysing-normative-data-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/analysing-normative-data-set/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe aim of the experiment of which I present some the results here was to get expectancy values for specific objects at specific location in a virtual kitchen. There were twenty possible objects and locations. After the completing these ratings, the participants were asked to rate the overall expectancy of those objects for a kitchen. The scale ranged from -100 (unexpected) to 100 (expected) and was continuous. Here I will visualise and interpret the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval task of pilot study</title>
      <link>/2017/11/retrieval-task-of-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/retrieval-task-of-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>I decided to write the retrieval task as MATLAB function not as script, so that this and the distractor task can be called multiple times from a simple script.
Originally posted on the 08/11/2018: I decided to drop the guess response option because there won’t be enough trials to analyse this conditio.n</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consideration on objects</title>
      <link>/2017/11/consideration-on-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/consideration-on-objects/</guid>
      <description> There could be the problem that unexpected objects have weird y-rotations if spawned at random locations. The towel could expected as kitchen towel.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on counterbalancing</title>
      <link>/2017/10/thoughts-on-counterbalancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/thoughts-on-counterbalancing/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find pairs of objects to counterbalance expected versus unexpected locations. * The first option, is to build pairs of relevant objects (e.g. knife – toaster) and think of three expected location for the first one that are unexpected for the second one. The problem here is that these are not the super expected locations and I would probably need to show in the normative studies that the expectancy is as hoped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various graphic settings in unity</title>
      <link>/2017/10/various-graphic-settings-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/various-graphic-settings-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>Graphical setting used for stimulus presentation:
 Use Legacy Cinematic Image Effects. Player &amp;gt; Other Settings &amp;gt; Color space &amp;gt; linear. Quality &amp;gt; Anti-Aliasing &amp;gt; 8x Multi Sampling.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting and feedback to first experiment</title>
      <link>/2017/10/lab-meeting-and-feedback-to-first-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/lab-meeting-and-feedback-to-first-experiment/</guid>
      <description>During our weekly lab meeting I got the following feedback pertaining to schemaVR:
 I should drop mixed condition and only use unexpected or expected locations to reduce the number of conditions. Another idea was to present objects in a sequence in order to create a temporal episode. It could be interesting in this context to look at the fragmentation hypothesis (Horner &amp;amp; Burgess, 2013, 2014) and see how my VR approach can be use to examine predictions of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts concerning Lew &amp; Howe (2016)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</guid>
      <description>After examining the stimuli photos from Lew &amp;amp; Howe (2016), I came to the conclusion that even schema-irrelevant objects have more or less expected locations. For instance, placing boots in the middle of the kitchen is unusual, but putting a hat on the kitchen table is less so.
Originally posted on the 26/10/2018: Schema-relevancy was measured on a scale of 1 to 10 (very usual to very unusual). Low rating (below 3) were regarded as relevant and rating above 5 were regarded as irrelevant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting and 3D models</title>
      <link>/2017/10/lighting-and-3d-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/lighting-and-3d-models/</guid>
      <description> To create realistic light, set environment lighting to colour and use white. To find suitable 3D models for my virtual kitchen, I looked for models on https://archive3d.net.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPC activity and graphics in Unity</title>
      <link>/2017/10/hpc-activity-and-graphics-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/hpc-activity-and-graphics-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>Frankland et al. (2005) reviews that HPC ripple activity is temporally correlated with cortical slow-wave spindles in the MPFC. This could be related to the integration of memories into existing schema.Unity tutorial on graphics:If I want to spawn objects at random locations, it would be problematic to pre-compute the lighting.Would it be a solution to be used mixed baking and have all the items, which do not change their location, as static because they have light maps?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use empty game objects as spawn points</title>
      <link>/2017/10/use-empty-game-objects-as-spawn-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/use-empty-game-objects-as-spawn-points/</guid>
      <description>Use empty game objects as spawn points to spawn objects in your environment. These can be dragged to certain position in the scene without specifying points in a Cartesian coordinate system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is my open notebook. My main homepage can be found here. This should be regarded as an attempt though to live up to the ideals that I have. It will take some time to develop good routines and incorporate those into my typical working day. This notebook will also witness my development as a researcher. Note that not everything will be perfect on here. If you find mistakes, please tell me!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>