<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian sequential designs are superior</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-sequential-designs-are-superior/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-sequential-designs-are-superior/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on a short talk that I gave at the MRC CBU on the 29 July 2020 for a session on statistical power, which can be found here. This repository also includes all the data and script that were used to run the simulations and to create the figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>/post/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/test/</guid>
      <description>   Header 1 Header 2 Header 3     Item 1 Item 2 Item 3   Item 1a Item 2a Item 3a      Header 1 Header 2 Header 3     Item 1 Item 2 Item 3   Item 1a Item 2a Item 3a    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing different methods to calculate Bayes factors for a simple model</title>
      <link>/post/comparing-different-methods-to-calculate-bayes-factors-for-a-simple-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/comparing-different-methods-to-calculate-bayes-factors-for-a-simple-model/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Comparing the four BF methods Evidence for null hypothesis: brms vs. ttestBF() How much more conservative is the bmrs approach? Directed vs. non-directed hypothesis Conclusion  Introduction In this post, I’d like to examine how different ways to calcualte Bayes factors (BF) compare with each other for a simple model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is my open notebook. My main homepage can be found here. This should be regarded as an attempt though to live up to the ideals that I have. It will take some time to develop good routines and incorporate those into my typical working day. This notebook will also witness my development as a researcher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>