<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Design on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/tags/research-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Design on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/tags/research-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3D location recall task in VR</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/3d-location-recall-task-in-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/3d-location-recall-task-in-vr/</guid>
      <description>As noted in the previous post, I want to create a 3D location recall task. I want that people are able to pick up objects from the floor and place them at the locations at which they think the objects were during encoding.
I found a good YouTube tutorial (see here) and adapted the respective script (see here), which needs to be added to the wand controllers to work. My version of the script will be uploaded later when it finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final design of schemaVR1</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-design-of-schemavr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-design-of-schemavr1/</guid>
      <description>My supervisor and I agreed on the final design while discussing the results of the pilot experiment. We both think that it is important to replicate Lew &amp;amp; Howe (2016) results if their test is used, but not if one uses 3AFC test. They used a Y/N location recognition task (“Was this object in this place before?”) and location recall task (2D picture version). I will develop a spatial 3D location recall task for the VR system to replicate the results in the first experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue with stimulus selection and some thoughts</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This entry contains thoughts and observations for the last couple of days because I was stuck with a problem and didn’t have a lot say. The problem was that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t controlled the number of times a location can serve as a foil when I had picked the set of object/locations pairs. This is indeed problematic because some locations were used four times. If you know which object was at a specific location, it isn’t really a foil anymore influencing subsequent trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change of design based on pilot study</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/change-of-design-based-on-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/change-of-design-based-on-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>I had the vague idea to do multivariate pattern analysis on the mPFC to decode specific schemas and to see how new objects/information is integrated in to those, but the problem might be that there are far too few trials to do that with the current design. It might also be interesting to look at memory reinstatement and how it is influence by schemas.
Today, I met with my supervisor and talked about the current design, about the ratings and general plan for this year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>