<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting and checking living/non-living words</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</guid>
      <description>Aim Here, I am selecting 200 words for a new project called noveltyVR, in which I am going to try to study the effect of novelty on something that was learned before. In this case, it will be a list of words that were incidentally encoded in a living/non-living judgement task. I will select 200 words from a published study, look up their properties in the MRC Psycholinguistic Database and create two lists that are used as old and new stimuli in a recognition task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> End of schemaVR1 and start of schemaVR2</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/05/end-of-schemavr1-and-start-of-schemavr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/05/end-of-schemavr1-and-start-of-schemavr2/</guid>
      <description>Today, I finished the data collection for schemaVR1. I collected 17 instead of 16 participants because I wanted to show the experiment to someone who then agreed to formally take part in this experiment.
The two major the results of this experiment are that the locations of objects that are generally unexpected in a kitchen are remembered better (measured by 3D location recall and 3AFC location recognition) than the locations of objects that are expected in a kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interim results of schemVR1</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/interim-results-of-schemvr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/interim-results-of-schemvr1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The current data collection is part of a broader attempt to pilot the design and to refine my hypotheses. The experiment itself is referred to as schemaVR1. The analyses that are pre-planned and post-hoc are clearly labelled.
This script was created to show the interim results. In order to be transparent to which extent I analysed the data before the conclusion of the data collection, I uploaded this version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interim results and future plans</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/interim-results-and-future-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/interim-results-and-future-plans/</guid>
      <description>I am currently caught up with collecting data for my first experiment, which I will henceforth call schemaVR1, working on my first year report and analysing the interim results. I have collected data from eight participant so far and already got number of significant results. This is quite impressive considering that I also have only twenty stimuli/trials. I will upload the pre-processing script alongside a script analysing the interim results in the next days in a separate GitHub repository, where I will provide more details, but a very robust, and already significant, finding is that the locations of unexpected objects are recalled more often than that of expected objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General update and plan for the future</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/03/general-update-and-plan-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/03/general-update-and-plan-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Even though the last post is basically a month ago, I am still committed to this diary. Therefore I thought to provide an update. I spent the last month with finishing the experiment and preparing its pre-registration. In that progress, I have started working on the R script that analyses the data to include it in the pre-registration. I want to use mixed linear models to analyse the data so that I can model the performance on individual trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed linear models</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/03/mixed-linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/03/mixed-linear-models/</guid>
      <description>Preface This work documents my attempt to understand the model structure of mixed linear models or multilevel models. I adapted a formula that I found on Wikipedia and work myself through the different models and test whether I am able to retrieve the different parameters with lmerTest. Bodo Winter&amp;rsquo;s tutorial on the lme was very useful for this. The main motivation for doing all this is to use basically model 5 in my analysis of my first experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D location recall task in VR</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/3d-location-recall-task-in-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/3d-location-recall-task-in-vr/</guid>
      <description>As noted in the previous post, I want to create a 3D location recall task. I want that people are able to pick up objects from the floor and place them at the locations at which they think the objects were during encoding.
I found a good YouTube tutorial (see here) and adapted the respective script (see here), which needs to be added to the wand controllers to work. My version of the script will be uploaded later when it finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final design of schemaVR1</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-design-of-schemavr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-design-of-schemavr1/</guid>
      <description>My supervisor and I agreed on the final design while discussing the results of the pilot experiment. We both think that it is important to replicate Lew &amp;amp; Howe (2016) results if their test is used, but not if one uses 3AFC test. They used a Y/N location recognition task (“Was this object in this place before?”) and location recall task (2D picture version). I will develop a spatial 3D location recall task for the VR system to replicate the results in the first experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final analysis of pilot data</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-analysis-of-pilot-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-analysis-of-pilot-data/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This script is about to check whether the parameters of the experiment (such as time in the VE, number of targets objects etc.) work to avoid either floor or ceiling effects. Note that the pre-encoding ratings (see below) were from different individuals.
Preliminary stuff Libraries &amp;amp; functions library(data.table) library(plyr) library(ggplot2) library(lme4) library(ez) library(BayesFactor) library(grid) pValue &amp;lt;-function(x, sign = &#39;=&#39;){ if (inherits(x, &amp;quot;lm&amp;quot;)){ s &amp;lt;- summary.lm(x) x &amp;lt;- pf(s$fstatistic[1L], s$fstatistic[2L], s$fstatistic[3L], lower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable naming</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/variable-naming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/variable-naming/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This document is out of date and will be replaced by a thourough convention of naming files and variables.
I recently realised that I am sometimes quite inconsistent when it comes to naming variables. I decided to stipulate a variable naming convention that I can stick to. This convention should be useable in the three major languages I use (R, Matlab, C#). That means I can’t for instance use dots within a name because it would only work in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking whether my data is saved correctly</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/checking-whether-my-data-is-saved-correctly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/checking-whether-my-data-is-saved-correctly/</guid>
      <description>Comment For the last days, I worked on the scripts of the retrieval task and the rating task (code can be found here). I successfully checked whether the data is saved correctly and can be used for analysis (see below). The next step now is to run a few pilot participants to see whether the task difficulty is appropriate.
Introduction I am about to start collecting pilot data to see whether the number of objects etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second attempt to select set of object/location pairs</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/second-attempt-to-select-set-of-object-location-pairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/second-attempt-to-select-set-of-object-location-pairs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is actually the second attempt to find a suitable set of object/location pairs (click here for the first attempt). The problem with the set I choose the first time is that some locations are used more than twice as foils during retrieval. This is an issue because once you know which object was at a specific location, it won&amp;rsquo;t work as a foil anymore.
Just as a reminder, the aim is to select a combination of twenty objects at twenty locations that cover the whole range of expectancy values together with two foil locations that match the expectancy of the targets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue with stimulus selection and some thoughts</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This entry contains thoughts and observations for the last couple of days because I was stuck with a problem and didn’t have a lot say. The problem was that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t controlled the number of times a location can serve as a foil when I had picked the set of object/locations pairs. This is indeed problematic because some locations were used four times. If you know which object was at a specific location, it isn’t really a foil anymore influencing subsequent trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing whether targets differ in rank from foils</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/testing-whether-targets-differ-in-rank-from-foils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/testing-whether-targets-differ-in-rank-from-foils/</guid>
      <description>Introduction On Friday I found a good combination of objects and locations (see here). Before I try this set in VR, it is important to make sure that the foils are not different from the targets in terms of the expectancy. To compare those, I calculate a repeated measure ANOVA and visualise it.
Used libraries and functions library(ggplot2) library(ez) library(tidyr) pValue &amp;lt;-function(x, sign = &#39;=&#39;){ if (inherits(x, &amp;quot;lm&amp;quot;)){ s &amp;lt;- summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulus selection for schemaVR1 (Attempt 1)</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/stimulus-selection-for-schemavr1-attempt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/stimulus-selection-for-schemavr1-attempt-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The aim is to select a certain number (20) of combinations of objects and locations that cover the whole range of expectancy values. The previous analysis of this data set can be found here. The code for the task can be found here.
Used libraries and functions library(ggplot2)  Loading the rating data I start with loading the raw data and creating a 20 x 20 x N matrix holding all 400 location ratings for all participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing normative data set</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/analysing-normative-data-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/analysing-normative-data-set/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The aim of the experiment of which I present some the results here was to get expectancy values for specific objects at specific location in a virtual kitchen. There were twenty possible objects and locations. After the completing these ratings, the participants were asked to rate the overall expectancy of those objects for a kitchen. The scale ranged from -100 (unexpected) to 100 (expected) and was continuous. Here I will visualise and interpret the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change of design based on pilot study</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/change-of-design-based-on-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/change-of-design-based-on-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>I had the vague idea to do multivariate pattern analysis on the mPFC to decode specific schemas and to see how new objects/information is integrated in to those, but the problem might be that there are far too few trials to do that with the current design. It might also be interesting to look at memory reinstatement and how it is influence by schemas.
Today, I met with my supervisor and talked about the current design, about the ratings and general plan for this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About my open notebook </title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/about-my-open-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/about-my-open-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Note (10/12/2018): This is outdated. See here for current approach.
I have just finished uploading old diary entries, which gives me the opportunity to reflect on what I have done so far and to get a bit more meta on the whole topic with this entry, which is the first one I am actually going to publish at the end of my (working) day. Some of the previous entries are quite short and initially weren’t written for the general public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing rating study</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/12/designing-rating-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/12/designing-rating-study/</guid>
      <description>11/12/2017: I finished the script, with which participants can rate a) the expectancy of an object in the room (kitchen) and b) the expectancy of a particular object at all possible twenty locations. To that regard, we decided to reverse the original order of ratings so that the overall expectancy of the objects for that room is rated at the very end. The reason for that is that otherwise one might be prone to rate schema irrelevant objects as highly unexpected (-100) in any location even though some are more expected than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of piloting</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/summary-of-piloting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/summary-of-piloting/</guid>
      <description>17/11/2017: Today, I run another pilot session and I realized that I should introduce practice trials of both the n-back distractor task and the recognition task to reduce the difference between the first and subsequent blocks. Before I can start with the normative study, I need to make sure how many objects I am going to need, how these objects are going to look like and whether these objects are appropriate because some had problems naming some objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/lab-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/lab-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Today I met with my supervisor and we also had lab meeting.  We have discussed the difficulty to counter-balance the expectedness of the objects and their locations in a true factorial design. For instance, it is nearly impossible to pair objects so that the expected location of one object is the unexpected location of the other object. We are interested in how the expectedness of an object and its location is related to memory and whether it is possible to get a u-shaped function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognition instructions for recollection and familiarity</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/recognition-instructions-for-recollection-and-familiarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/recognition-instructions-for-recollection-and-familiarity/</guid>
      <description>Following feedback I changed the instruction for the recognition task so that they are in line with Bastin et al. (2014). The respective part of the instruction were changed to:
 If you pressed &amp;lt;&amp;lt;y&amp;gt;&amp;gt; for yes, you will need to indicate whether you recollected this by pressing &amp;lt;&amp;lt;r&amp;gt;&amp;gt; or whether this object was only familiar by pressing &amp;lt;&amp;lt;f&amp;gt;&amp;gt;. You recollected an object if you see it and recall specific details about it (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running RMarkdown on CBU computer and first pilot session</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</guid>
      <description>The issues I am describing here are probably most interesting for people also working on a MRC-CBU computer because MRC-CBU’s specific cyber-security regulations. When I tried to create a new RMarkdown file, I got an error message that the package ‘rprojroot’ could not be found.
These the things that I tried and eventually worked:
 I installed the package as a source package, because there is no binary version of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval task of pilot study</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/retrieval-task-of-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/retrieval-task-of-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>I decided to write the retrieval task as MATLAB function not as script, so that this and the distractor task can be called multiple times from a simple script.
Originally posted on the 08/11/2018: I decided to drop the guess response option because there won’t be enough trials to analyse this conditio.n</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consideration on objects</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/consideration-on-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/consideration-on-objects/</guid>
      <description> There could be the problem that unexpected objects have weird y-rotations if spawned at random locations. The towel could expected as kitchen towel.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on counterbalancing</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-on-counterbalancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-on-counterbalancing/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find pairs of objects to counterbalance expected versus unexpected locations. * The first option, is to build pairs of relevant objects (e.g. knife – toaster) and think of three expected location for the first one that are unexpected for the second one. The problem here is that these are not the super expected locations and I would probably need to show in the normative studies that the expectancy is as hoped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various graphic settings in unity</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/various-graphic-settings-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/various-graphic-settings-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>Graphical setting used for stimulus presentation:
 Use Legacy Cinematic Image Effects. Player &amp;gt; Other Settings &amp;gt; Color space &amp;gt; linear. Quality &amp;gt; Anti-Aliasing &amp;gt; 8x Multi Sampling.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting/</guid>
      <description>During our weekly lab meeting I got the following feedback pertaining to project 1 (schema-memory-VR; see here):
 I should drop mixed condition and only use unexpected or expected locations to reduce the number of conditions. Another idea was to present objects in a sequence in order to create a temporal episode. It could be interesting in this context to look at the fragmentation hypothesis (Horner &amp;amp; Burgess, 2013, 2014) and see how my VR approach can be use to examine predictions of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting and feedback to first experiment</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting-and-feedback-to-first-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting-and-feedback-to-first-experiment/</guid>
      <description>During our weekly lab meeting I got the following feedback pertaining to schemaVR:
 I should drop mixed condition and only use unexpected or expected locations to reduce the number of conditions. Another idea was to present objects in a sequence in order to create a temporal episode. It could be interesting in this context to look at the fragmentation hypothesis (Horner &amp;amp; Burgess, 2013, 2014) and see how my VR approach can be use to examine predictions of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts concerning Lew &amp; Howe (2016)</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</guid>
      <description>After examining the stimuli photos from Lew &amp;amp; Howe (2016), I came to the conclusion that even schema-irrelevant objects have more or less expected locations. For instance, placing boots in the middle of the kitchen is unusual, but putting a hat on the kitchen table is less so.
Originally posted on the 26/10/2018: Schema-relevancy was measured on a scale of 1 to 10 (very usual to very unusual). Low rating (below 3) were regarded as relevant and rating above 5 were regarded as irrelevant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting and 3D models</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lighting-and-3d-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lighting-and-3d-models/</guid>
      <description> To create realistic light, set environment lighting to colour and use white. To find suitable 3D models for my virtual kitchen, I looked for models on https://archive3d.net.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPC activity and graphics in Unity</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/hpc-activity-and-graphics-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/hpc-activity-and-graphics-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>Frankland et al. (2005) reviews that HPC ripple activity is temporally correlated with cortical slow-wave spindles in the MPFC. This could be related to the integration of memories into existing schema.Unity tutorial on graphics:If I want to spawn objects at random locations, it would be problematic to pre-compute the lighting.Would it be a solution to be used mixed baking and have all the items, which do not change their location, as static because they have light maps?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use empty game objects as spawn points</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/use-empty-game-objects-as-spawn-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/use-empty-game-objects-as-spawn-points/</guid>
      <description>Use empty game objects as spawn points to spawn objects in your environment. These can be dragged to certain position in the scene without specifying points in a Cartesian coordinate system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>