<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pilot Study on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/tags/pilot-study/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pilot Study on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/tags/pilot-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Change of design based on pilot study</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/change-of-design-based-on-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/change-of-design-based-on-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>I had the vague idea to do multivariate pattern analysis on the mPFC to decode specific schemas and to see how new objects/information is integrated in to those, but the problem might be that there are far too few trials to do that with the current design. It might also be interesting to look at memory reinstatement and how it is influence by schemas.
Today, I met with my supervisor and talked about the current design, about the ratings and general plan for this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of piloting</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/summary-of-piloting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/summary-of-piloting/</guid>
      <description>17/11/2017: Today, I run another pilot session and I realized that I should introduce practice trials of both the n-back distractor task and the recognition task to reduce the difference between the first and subsequent blocks. Before I can start with the normative study, I need to make sure how many objects I am going to need, how these objects are going to look like and whether these objects are appropriate because some had problems naming some objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running RMarkdown on CBU computer and first pilot session</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</guid>
      <description>The issues I am describing here are probably most interesting for people also working on a MRC-CBU computer because MRC-CBU’s specific cyber-security regulations. When I tried to create a new RMarkdown file, I got an error message that the package ‘rprojroot’ could not be found.
These the things that I tried and eventually worked:
 I installed the package as a source package, because there is no binary version of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval task of pilot study</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/retrieval-task-of-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/retrieval-task-of-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>I decided to write the retrieval task as MATLAB function not as script, so that this and the distractor task can be called multiple times from a simple script.
Originally posted on the 08/11/2018: I decided to drop the guess response option because there won’t be enough trials to analyse this conditio.n</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consideration on objects</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/consideration-on-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/consideration-on-objects/</guid>
      <description> There could be the problem that unexpected objects have weird y-rotations if spawned at random locations. The towel could expected as kitchen towel.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on counterbalancing</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-on-counterbalancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-on-counterbalancing/</guid>
      <description>Trying to find pairs of objects to counterbalance expected versus unexpected locations. * The first option, is to build pairs of relevant objects (e.g. knife – toaster) and think of three expected location for the first one that are unexpected for the second one. The problem here is that these are not the super expected locations and I would probably need to show in the normative studies that the expectancy is as hoped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>