<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rmarkdown on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/tags/rmarkdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rmarkdown on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/tags/rmarkdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior deliberation on analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2019/03/prior-deliberation-on-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2019/03/prior-deliberation-on-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Aim of this document The aim of this document is to accompany the design analysis for noveltyVR (see here) and to shed light on the deliberations concerning the planned analysis.
The planned design is a 2 x 2 x 2 design with one between and two within subject factors. There will be a novelty and a control group (Factor N) and we will examine recollection/familiarity (Factor M) for weakly/strongly learned words (Factor E).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting and checking living/non-living words</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</guid>
      <description>Aim Here, I am selecting 200 words for a new project called noveltyVR, in which I am going to try to study the effect of novelty on something that was learned before. In this case, it will be a list of words that were incidentally encoded in a living/non-living judgement task. I will select 200 words from a published study, look up their properties in the MRC Psycholinguistic Database and create two lists that are used as old and new stimuli in a recognition task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interim results of schemVR1</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/interim-results-of-schemvr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/04/interim-results-of-schemvr1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The current data collection is part of a broader attempt to pilot the design and to refine my hypotheses. The experiment itself is referred to as schemaVR1. The analyses that are pre-planned and post-hoc are clearly labelled.
This script was created to show the interim results. In order to be transparent to which extent I analysed the data before the conclusion of the data collection, I uploaded this version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed linear models</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/03/mixed-linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/03/mixed-linear-models/</guid>
      <description>Preface This work documents my attempt to understand the model structure of mixed linear models or multilevel models. I adapted a formula that I found on Wikipedia and work myself through the different models and test whether I am able to retrieve the different parameters with lmerTest. Bodo Winter&amp;rsquo;s tutorial on the lme was very useful for this. The main motivation for doing all this is to use basically model 5 in my analysis of my first experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final analysis of pilot data</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-analysis-of-pilot-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/02/final-analysis-of-pilot-data/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This script is about to check whether the parameters of the experiment (such as time in the VE, number of targets objects etc.) work to avoid either floor or ceiling effects. Note that the pre-encoding ratings (see below) were from different individuals.
Preliminary stuff Libraries &amp;amp; functions library(data.table) library(plyr) library(ggplot2) library(lme4) library(ez) library(BayesFactor) library(grid) pValue &amp;lt;-function(x, sign = &#39;=&#39;){ if (inherits(x, &amp;quot;lm&amp;quot;)){ s &amp;lt;- summary.lm(x) x &amp;lt;- pf(s$fstatistic[1L], s$fstatistic[2L], s$fstatistic[3L], lower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking whether my data is saved correctly</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/checking-whether-my-data-is-saved-correctly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/checking-whether-my-data-is-saved-correctly/</guid>
      <description>Comment For the last days, I worked on the scripts of the retrieval task and the rating task (code can be found here). I successfully checked whether the data is saved correctly and can be used for analysis (see below). The next step now is to run a few pilot participants to see whether the task difficulty is appropriate.
Introduction I am about to start collecting pilot data to see whether the number of objects etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second attempt to select set of object/location pairs</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/second-attempt-to-select-set-of-object-location-pairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/second-attempt-to-select-set-of-object-location-pairs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is actually the second attempt to find a suitable set of object/location pairs (click here for the first attempt). The problem with the set I choose the first time is that some locations are used more than twice as foils during retrieval. This is an issue because once you know which object was at a specific location, it won&amp;rsquo;t work as a foil anymore.
Just as a reminder, the aim is to select a combination of twenty objects at twenty locations that cover the whole range of expectancy values together with two foil locations that match the expectancy of the targets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing whether targets differ in rank from foils</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/testing-whether-targets-differ-in-rank-from-foils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/testing-whether-targets-differ-in-rank-from-foils/</guid>
      <description>Introduction On Friday I found a good combination of objects and locations (see here). Before I try this set in VR, it is important to make sure that the foils are not different from the targets in terms of the expectancy. To compare those, I calculate a repeated measure ANOVA and visualise it.
Used libraries and functions library(ggplot2) library(ez) library(tidyr) pValue &amp;lt;-function(x, sign = &#39;=&#39;){ if (inherits(x, &amp;quot;lm&amp;quot;)){ s &amp;lt;- summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulus selection for schemaVR1 (Attempt 1)</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/stimulus-selection-for-schemavr1-attempt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/stimulus-selection-for-schemavr1-attempt-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The aim is to select a certain number (20) of combinations of objects and locations that cover the whole range of expectancy values. The previous analysis of this data set can be found here. The code for the task can be found here.
Used libraries and functions library(ggplot2)  Loading the rating data I start with loading the raw data and creating a 20 x 20 x N matrix holding all 400 location ratings for all participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing normative data set</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/analysing-normative-data-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/01/analysing-normative-data-set/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The aim of the experiment of which I present some the results here was to get expectancy values for specific objects at specific location in a virtual kitchen. There were twenty possible objects and locations. After the completing these ratings, the participants were asked to rate the overall expectancy of those objects for a kitchen. The scale ranged from -100 (unexpected) to 100 (expected) and was continuous. Here I will visualise and interpret the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running RMarkdown on CBU computer and first pilot session</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</guid>
      <description>The issues I am describing here are probably most interesting for people also working on a MRC-CBU computer because MRC-CBU’s specific cyber-security regulations. When I tried to create a new RMarkdown file, I got an error message that the package ‘rprojroot’ could not be found.
These the things that I tried and eventually worked:
 I installed the package as a source package, because there is no binary version of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>