<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Schema on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/tags/schema/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Schema on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/tags/schema/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title> End of schemaVR1 and start of schemaVR2</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/05/end-of-schemavr1-and-start-of-schemavr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/05/end-of-schemavr1-and-start-of-schemavr2/</guid>
      <description>Today, I finished the data collection for schemaVR1. I collected 17 instead of 16 participants because I wanted to show the experiment to someone who then agreed to formally take part in this experiment.
The two major the results of this experiment are that the locations of objects that are generally unexpected in a kitchen are remembered better (measured by 3D location recall and 3AFC location recognition) than the locations of objects that are expected in a kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting/</guid>
      <description>During our weekly lab meeting I got the following feedback pertaining to project 1 (schema-memory-VR; see here):
 I should drop mixed condition and only use unexpected or expected locations to reduce the number of conditions. Another idea was to present objects in a sequence in order to create a temporal episode. It could be interesting in this context to look at the fragmentation hypothesis (Horner &amp;amp; Burgess, 2013, 2014) and see how my VR approach can be use to examine predictions of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab meeting and feedback to first experiment</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting-and-feedback-to-first-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/lab-meeting-and-feedback-to-first-experiment/</guid>
      <description>During our weekly lab meeting I got the following feedback pertaining to schemaVR:
 I should drop mixed condition and only use unexpected or expected locations to reduce the number of conditions. Another idea was to present objects in a sequence in order to create a temporal episode. It could be interesting in this context to look at the fragmentation hypothesis (Horner &amp;amp; Burgess, 2013, 2014) and see how my VR approach can be use to examine predictions of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts concerning Lew &amp; Howe (2016)</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</guid>
      <description>After examining the stimuli photos from Lew &amp;amp; Howe (2016), I came to the conclusion that even schema-irrelevant objects have more or less expected locations. For instance, placing boots in the middle of the kitchen is unusual, but putting a hat on the kitchen table is less so.
Originally posted on the 26/10/2018: Schema-relevancy was measured on a scale of 1 to 10 (very usual to very unusual). Low rating (below 3) were regarded as relevant and rating above 5 were regarded as irrelevant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>