<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>general on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing different methods to calculate Bayes factors for a simple mode</title>
      <link>/2020/07/comparing-different-methods-to-calculate-bayes-factors-for-a-simple-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/comparing-different-methods-to-calculate-bayes-factors-for-a-simple-mode/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Comparing the four BF methods Evidence for null hypothesis: brms vs. ttestBF() How much more conservative is the bmrs approach? Directed vs. non-directed hypothesis Conclusion  Introduction In this post, I’d like to examine how different ways to calcualte Bayes factors (BF) compare with each other for a simple model. This simulation was run on my department’s HPC using the rslurm package: the corresponding R code, data and .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of SD under the null hypothesis</title>
      <link>/2019/04/effect-of-sd-under-the-null-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/effect-of-sd-under-the-null-hypothesis/</guid>
      <description>Outset of the problem I recently discussed generating data for a power/design analysis and the following problem came up. Does the standard deviation (SD) has an influence on the test statistics (t-value, p-value, BF) under the null hypothesis? The noise in the or the SD of the data should have no effect. To understand this, look at Cohen&amp;rsquo;s D, which is the mean divided by the SD. Under the null hypothesis will always be zero because the mean is zero regardless how big the SD is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior deliberation on analysis</title>
      <link>/2019/03/prior-deliberation-on-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/prior-deliberation-on-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Aim of this document The aim of this document is to accompany the design analysis for noveltyVR (see here) and to shed light on the deliberations concerning the planned analysis.
The planned design is a 2 x 2 x 2 design with one between and two within subject factors. There will be a novelty and a control group (Factor N) and we will examine recollection/familiarity (Factor M) for weakly/strongly learned words (Factor E).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General update and plan for the future</title>
      <link>/2018/03/general-update-and-plan-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/general-update-and-plan-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Even though the last post is basically a month ago, I am still committed to this diary. Therefore I thought to provide an update. I spent the last month with finishing the experiment and preparing its pre-registration. In that progress, I have started working on the R script that analyses the data to include it in the pre-registration. I want to use mixed linear models to analyse the data so that I can model the performance on individual trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed linear models</title>
      <link>/2018/03/mixed-linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/mixed-linear-models/</guid>
      <description>Preface This work documents my attempt to understand the model structure of mixed linear models or multilevel models. I adapted a formula that I found on Wikipedia and work myself through the different models and test whether I am able to retrieve the different parameters with lmerTest. Bodo Winter&amp;rsquo;s tutorial on the lme was very useful for this. The main motivation for doing all this is to use basically model 5 in my analysis of my first experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable naming</title>
      <link>/2018/02/variable-naming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/variable-naming/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This document is out of date and will be replaced by a thourough convention of naming files and variables.
I recently realised that I am sometimes quite inconsistent when it comes to naming variables. I decided to stipulate a variable naming convention that I can stick to. This convention should be useable in the three major languages I use (R, Matlab, C#). That means I can’t for instance use dots within a name because it would only work in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue with stimulus selection and some thoughts</title>
      <link>/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/issue-with-stimulus-selection-and-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This entry contains thoughts and observations for the last couple of days because I was stuck with a problem and didn’t have a lot say. The problem was that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t controlled the number of times a location can serve as a foil when I had picked the set of object/locations pairs. This is indeed problematic because some locations were used four times. If you know which object was at a specific location, it isn’t really a foil anymore influencing subsequent trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About my open notebook </title>
      <link>/2018/01/about-my-open-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/about-my-open-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Note (10/12/2018): This is outdated. See here for current approach.
I have just finished uploading old diary entries, which gives me the opportunity to reflect on what I have done so far and to get a bit more meta on the whole topic with this entry, which is the first one I am actually going to publish at the end of my (working) day. Some of the previous entries are quite short and initially weren’t written for the general public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running RMarkdown on CBU computer and first pilot session</title>
      <link>/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/running-rmarkdown-on-cbu-computer-and-first-pilot-session/</guid>
      <description>The issues I am describing here are probably most interesting for people also working on a MRC-CBU computer because MRC-CBU’s specific cyber-security regulations. When I tried to create a new RMarkdown file, I got an error message that the package ‘rprojroot’ could not be found.
These the things that I tried and eventually worked:
 I installed the package as a source package, because there is no binary version of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts concerning Lew &amp; Howe (2016)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/thoughts-concerning-lew-howe-2016/</guid>
      <description>After examining the stimuli photos from Lew &amp;amp; Howe (2016), I came to the conclusion that even schema-irrelevant objects have more or less expected locations. For instance, placing boots in the middle of the kitchen is unusual, but putting a hat on the kitchen table is less so.
Originally posted on the 26/10/2018: Schema-relevancy was measured on a scale of 1 to 10 (very usual to very unusual). Low rating (below 3) were regarded as relevant and rating above 5 were regarded as irrelevant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting and 3D models</title>
      <link>/2017/10/lighting-and-3d-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/lighting-and-3d-models/</guid>
      <description> To create realistic light, set environment lighting to colour and use white. To find suitable 3D models for my virtual kitchen, I looked for models on https://archive3d.net.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPC activity and graphics in Unity</title>
      <link>/2017/10/hpc-activity-and-graphics-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/hpc-activity-and-graphics-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>Frankland et al. (2005) reviews that HPC ripple activity is temporally correlated with cortical slow-wave spindles in the MPFC. This could be related to the integration of memories into existing schema. Unity tutorial on graphics:  If I want to spawn objects at random locations, it would be problematic to pre-compute the lighting. Would it be a solution to be used mixed baking and have all the items, which do not change their location, as static because they have light maps?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>