<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noveltyvr on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://jaquent.github.io/tags/noveltyvr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Noveltyvr on Jörn Alexander Quent&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaquent.github.io/tags/noveltyvr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design analysis for noveltyVR</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2019/03/design-analysis-for-noveltyvr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2019/03/design-analysis-for-noveltyvr/</guid>
      <description>Aim of this document The aim of this document is to conduct a design analysis for a fixed N design using one-sided Bayesian t-test. This analysis will inform our choice of N for a registered report. The planned experiment is a 2 x 2 x 2 design with one between- and two within-subject factors. Without going into too much detail, there will be a novelty and a control group (Factor N) and we will examine recollection/familiarity (Factor M) for weakly/strongly learned words (Factor E).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior deliberation on analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2019/03/prior-deliberation-on-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2019/03/prior-deliberation-on-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Aim of this document The aim of this document is to accompany the design analysis for noveltyVR (see here) and to shed light on the deliberations concerning the planned analysis.
The planned design is a 2 x 2 x 2 design with one between and two within subject factors. There will be a novelty and a control group (Factor N) and we will examine recollection/familiarity (Factor M) for weakly/strongly learned words (Factor E).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting and checking living/non-living words</title>
      <link>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaquent.github.io/2018/11/selecting-and-checking-living-non-living-words/</guid>
      <description>Aim Here, I am selecting 200 words for a new project called noveltyVR, in which I am going to try to study the effect of novelty on something that was learned before. In this case, it will be a list of words that were incidentally encoded in a living/non-living judgement task. I will select 200 words from a published study, look up their properties in the MRC Psycholinguistic Database and create two lists that are used as old and new stimuli in a recognition task.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>